1944年 一个超自然事物研究小组
In 1944 a team of paranormal researchers,
在苏格兰海岸执行秘密任务时
Together with the US Army, rescued a strange creature
与美军一起解救了一只奇异生物
During a classified mission off the coast of Scotland
这只生物被秘密收养
Sectetly adopted, this creature
与我们生活在一起
Now lives among us.
他爱吃糖果 爱看电视
It loves candy and TV.
他的代号：地狱男爵
Code Name: Hellboy
（新墨西哥州 道格拉斯美军基地）
（1955年 圣诞夜）
孩子 把那糟糕的木偶戏关掉吧
My son, will you turn off that wretched puppet?
去刷牙
Brush your teeth.
别叫他木偶
Don't call him a puppet.
你说什么
I beg your pardon.
霍迪·多蒂不是木偶
Look, he's not a puppet.
他是真人
Howdy doody's real.
Well… he's real.
得跟滴滴嘟嘟先生说再见了
Mr. deedee doodoo will have to say good night.
不要
Oh, no.
记住 当圣诞老人从烟囱下来时
And remember, you have to be asleep
你得睡着
When he comes down the chimney.
连个烟囱都没有 爷爷
It's not even a chimney, pop.
他自有办法的
He has his ways.
那我想醒着看他怎么下来
Then I want to wait up. watch him do it.
胡闹
Nonsense.
那我想听故事
Okay. I want a story then.
不不不 今晚可没故事
Oh, no, no, no. no stories tonight.
就一个嘛 然后我就去睡觉
Just one. and then I'll go to bed.
听完马上就睡
Right away.
我还会去刷牙 我保证
Then I'll brush my teeth, I promise.
据说 在开天辟地之时
It is said that at the dawn of time,
人类 野兽和所有魔族生物
Man, beast and all magical beings
共同生活在树神艾格林之下
Lived together under Aiglin the father tree.
但人类的心脏天生有一个洞
But man had been created with a hole in his heart,
财富 权利或知识都无法填充它
A hole that no possession, power or knowledge could fill.
因为人类永无止境的欲望
And in his infinite greed,
他们企图占领整个地球
Man dreamt of expanding his dominion over the entire earth.
许多精灵 魔鬼和妖精
The blood of many an elf, ogre and goblin
都惨死在人类的屠刀下
Was spilled in their war with man.
独臂精灵王巴罗
And king balor, the one-armed king of elfland,
目睹了这场屠杀 他绝望而且恐惧
Watched the slaughter in dread and despair.
直到有一天 妖精中的铸造大师
But one day, the master of the goblin blacksmiths
提出要为精灵王打造一支黄金军团
Offered to build the king a golden mechanical army,
由4900名士兵组成
"Seventy times 70 soldiers
他们永不知疲倦 没人可以阻挡
That would never know hunger and could not be stopped.
努阿达王子恳求精灵王批准这个建议
Prince nuada begged his father to agree.
精灵王最终说 为我建造这支军团吧
"Build me this army, " the king said.
这样 他造出了一顶魔法王冠
So a magical crown was forged
它将让具有皇族血统的人
That would allow those of royal blood
领导这支黄金军团
To command the golden army
但前提是他的皇威不能被挑战
If unchallenged.
我是精灵王巴罗 黄金军团的领导者
"I am king balor, leader of the golden army.
有人胆敢挑战我的皇威吗
"Is there anyone who disputes my right?"
没人回应
And in his throne room no one challenged his word.
但 等等 如果有人挑战呢
But, wait, what if someone could challenge him?
他们会决斗吗
Would they have a fight?
应该会
Well, most likely.
挑战是必须回应的
A challenge must be answered.
你想知道故事的结果吗
But do you want to hear the end of this story or not?
想听 想听
Yes, please.
好
Right.
于是 世界的局势改变了
So the world was changed,
当人类再次进军的时候
And the next time the humans marched,
他们感到大地在脚下振颤
They felt the earth tremble beneath their feet
天空被魔影笼罩
And saw the sky darken with monstrous shapes.
黄金军团没有怜悯 忠诚或者痛苦
The golden army had no remorse, felt no loyalty or pain.
但精灵王万分悔恨
And king balor's heart grew heavy with regret.
所以 他宣布停战 并把王冠分成三部分
So he called a truce and divided the crown in three pieces,
一个给人类保管 剩下的留给自己
One for the humans, and two for himself.
作为交换 人类获得了城市
In exchange, man would keep to the cities
而魔族生物则拥有森林
And the magical beings would own the forests.
这停战协定将会被
This truce would be honored
世世代代尊奉下去
by their sons and the sons of their sons
直到世界消亡
Until the end of time.
但努阿达王子并不信任人类的承诺
But prince nuada did not believe in the promises of man.
据说他离开家乡
And it is said that he went into exile,
并发誓会在他的人民最需要他的时候回来
Vowing to return the day his people needed him most.
于是 黄金军团无人支配
So the golden army lay dormant,
并被囚于大地之中 等待着召唤
Locked inside the earth, waiting.
直到今天
And there it is to this day,
他们仍在等待王冠重新合而为一的时刻
Awaiting the day the crown is made whole again.
他们安静地等待着 永不消亡
Silent, still and indestructible."
永不消亡是什么意思
Wow. what does it mean "industrable"?
永不消亡
Indestructible.
永不消…
Indestruct…
就是说没人可以消灭它们
It means no one can destroy them.
该睡了 孩子
Go to sleep, my son.
这只是个故事 对吧 爷爷
But it's just a story, right, pops?
是真的
Is it now?
别逗了
Yeah, come on.
那些人不可能是真的
Those guys, they can't be real.
孩子 总有一天你会明白
Well, my son, I'm sure you'll find out.
《地狱男爵2：黄金军团》
你在这呆多久了 朋友
How long have you been there, my friend?
它们在那边
They're over there.
我今天买来的
I bought them today.
还没喂呢
I haven't fed them at all.
我先上去 你跟着我
I will go up first. you will follow.
记住 文克先生 别害羞
And remember, mr. wink, don't be shy.
（曼哈顿 9月26日 20点）
下一件拍品 776号
Next lot. number 776.
是一尊地位很高的雕像
This is an important votive figure,
丰饶女神 时代大约在
A fertility goddess dating.
西元前10000到15000年
Approximately 15, 000 to 10, 000 b.c
这件拍卖品是在
This was found in a loess deposit
离夏侬30米的黄土坑里发现的
In a terrace about 30 meters from the shannon river.
底价为30万美元
And we'll open the bidding at $300, 000.
30万美元
Three hundred thousand.
32万5千 谢谢
Three hundred and twenty-five, thank you.
35万 谢谢你
Three hundred and fifty, thank you.
37万5千
Three seventy-five.
Three hundred and seventy-five.
37万5千一次 两次 成交
Going once. going twice. sold.
下件拍品 777号
And now we move on to our next item, lot 777,
一片来自贝茨莫拉圣冠的碎片
A piece of the royal crown of bethmoora.
它诉说着
The origin of this piece harkens back
天之子的传奇
To the saga of the sons of the earth
并且掌握着黄金军团的命运
And the creation of the fabled golden army.
这就是我们的下一件拍卖品
And here it is, our next item.
先生们女士们 请不要离座
Ladies and gentlemen, please keep your seats.
拍卖马上恢复
The auction will restart shortly.
只是暂时停电
I'm sure this is just a temporary loss of power.
现在是首次拍卖的
Now, for the first time at auction,
贝茨莫拉圣冠的碎片
A piece of the royal crown of bethmoora,
从一个早已失落的文明向我们走来
Coming to us from a long lost culture.
早已失落吗
Lost?
根本没有
Not at all.
也许是被你们遗忘了
Forgotten by you, perhaps,
但却仍然生机勃勃
But very, very much alive.
你是谁 先生
Who are you, sir?
先生 请说明你的身份 你不可以…
Sir, please identify yourself. you can't just…
我是努阿达·西弗兰斯王子
I am prince nuada silverlance
我来这里取回属于我的东西
And I am here, sir, to reclaim what is rightfully mine.
警卫 叫警卫
Security. call security!
你知不知道你在干什么
What do you think you're doing?
太野蛮了
This is outrageous.
随便拿吧 求求你
Take what you want. please leave.
什么都行 都给你
Anything, take anything.
闭嘴
Be quiet.
坐下
Sit down!
你们这群自大无知肤浅的东西
Proud, empty, hollow things that you are.
让你们牢记恐惧黑暗的滋味
Let this remind you why you once feared the dark.
（新泽西州 特顿市 22点08分）
（超自然研究防御中心）
费斯蒂克 咱们得谈谈
Fishstick. we have to talk.
秘密活动
Undercover.
他不懂这个词什么意思吗
Can't he get the meaning of the word?
听着 我们仍是由政府资助
Look, we are still government-funded.
我们仍是个秘密 肮脏的秘密
We are still a secret, although a dirty secret, if you ask me.
按官方的说法 我们根本不存在
Officially we do not exist, you see.
所以当我们拿到这些 就是个麻烦事儿
So that's the problem when we get these.
地铁 高速公路 还有公园
Subway. highway. park.
他还在这张里摆造型 又签了名
And he posed for this one and gave an autograph.
我封锁了全部照片和视频
I suppress each photo. cell phone videos.
花了我好大一笔 但还是被传到了网上
They cost me a fortune and they show up on youtube.
我恨Youtube这个网站
God, I hate youtube.
他只是想让外面知道我们做了什么
Well, he just wants the world outside to know what we do,
不 是他做了什么
What he does.
他讨厌我
He loathes me.
我不这么想
I don't think so.
不是吗
No?
射击训练
Target practice.
天哪
Oh, dear.
然后他把这个到处贴
And then he posts them around.
你知道这让我有什么感觉
Do you know how that makes me feel?
发生什么事儿了
What's going on?
哦 今天周五
h, it's friday.
我告诉你 他恨我
I tell you, fishstick, he hates me.
他就是来杀我的
He's out to destroy me.
现在我的街头血条很低
My street cred is low.
街头血条是什么
Street cred?
就是我的能量
My mojo.
华盛顿那边肯定在想我是否已抓到他了
Washington, they're wondering if I've got the stuff.
你以为我的工作轻松吗
You think I have an easy job?
你以为我喜欢招人烦吗
Do you think I enjoy being a pain in the neck?
我得吃药了
I am medicated.
这不是糖
I mean, this is not candy.
是抗酸剂…
This is… it's an antacid.
是啊 还是非处方药呢
Yes, it's an over-the-counter medicine,
但 这是药
But this is medicine.
我很担心 你知道的
You see, I worry because, you know,
我是说 我 我们毕竟是
I mean, I am, we are, after all,
总之我们只是干活的
We're just humble public servants.
这不关你的事 他有点过火
It's not about you. he's acting out.
因为他和丽兹之间有点紧张
Things are a little tense with liz.
怎么紧张 紧张什么
Tense? how tense? tense how?
你知道 就像平常人一样
Well, you know, the usual.
新夫妻得有个磨合期
A new couple making adjustments.
- 他们会吵架 - 吵架是吗
- They argue. - They argue, huh?
- 偶尔会吵 - 吵到什么程度呢
- Sometimes. - How bad?
和其他人都一样
Like everybody else.
他们也有悲欢离合
They have good days and bad days.
我跟你没完
I'm not done with you.
你好亚伯
Hey, abe.
红大个 到这边来
Red, come back here!
真是的
Manning.
把你的衣服捡起来
Pick up your clothes!
好 好 好
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
把你的东西拿走
Put away your things!
小心点哥们 她正在气头上
Watch it, boys, she's on fire.
话说回来 他们吵得可真凶
Then again, there are the really bad days.
我可不怕你 你知道的
I'm not afraid of you, you know.
你应该怕我 看看这一团乱
You should be. look at this mess. look around.
我有个规矩 别碰我的东西
I have one rule. don't touch my stuff.
明白了 搞的乱七八糟就是你的规矩
Oh, I get it. that's your rule. okay.
就这一个规矩 我很好说话
The one and only. I'm easy.
怎么可能
How's that even possible?
都是你的东西呢
Everything is your stuff.
一样的CD和唱片
The same cd, lp.
这是全绿的专辑
It's all green.
不能在CD机上听这个
You can't listen to all green on cd.
但值得收藏
But it's good to keep.
可这是黑胶唱片啊 红大个
And an eight-track. an eight-track, red?
总有一天人们会认识到自己的错误
Yeah, well, one day, the world's gonna realize its mistake.
黑胶唱片才是正道
Eight-track was the way to go, baby.
来 孩子们 可以出来了
Come on, kids, you can come out now.
这就对了 都结束了
That's right, it's all over. that's right.
那我呢 红大个
And what about me, red?
我需要空间
I need some space.
起码能找到我的牙刷
At least enough to find my toothbrush.
牙刷吗 等一下
Toothbrush? wait a minute.
不就在那嘛
It's right there.
红大个 我不能这样过下去了
Red, I can't live like this.
妈的
Oh, damn.
得走了 我们都得走了
Gotta go. we all gotta go.
是紧急事件 对吧
It's an emergency, right?
走吧
Let's go.
红大个 红大个
Red. red!
等一下
Hold on a sec.
天哪 是曼宁 丽兹你自己小心点
Oh, jeez, it's manning. watch yourself, liz.
红大个 红大个
Red. red!
听着
Listen.
- 曼宁 - 嘿
- Manning. - Hi.
我们得去曼哈顿的闹市区
We're going to downtown manhattan.
好啊 肯定很好玩
Yeah, it'll be fun.
闹市区 很危险的
Downtown. very dangerous.
对你来说很危险
Dangerous for you.
当然对我也很危险
And for me.
我知道你想去外面世界
Now, I know you dream of the outside world,
但是相信我 外面世界不好玩的
But, trust me, it's not that great.
那里很野蛮 很糟糕
It's savage, as a matter of fact. bad.
来吧伙计们 咱们出去吧
Come on, fellas, let's get this out of here.
但是这个很不错
These, on the other hand, are good.
古巴雪茄
Cuban.
很好
Good.
被人看到的话
Being seen?
很糟
Bad.
正确 我买了好几箱
Exactly. I confiscated a box of these,
我会再给你的
And I'll get you some more.
但今晚在外面的时候你得帮我个忙
But you've gotta do me a little favor tonight, out there.
你必须非常非常…
You have to be… you have to be very, very…
谨慎
Discreet.
- 什么 谢谢 对 - 不客气
- What? thank you. yes. - You're welcome.
谨慎
Discreet.
当个隐形人 进去 出来
Invisible. in and out.
你能吗
Really?
要是我愿意 我也可以谨慎
Hey, I can be discreet if I wanna be.
我跟踪过你和迈尔斯 记得吗
I followed you and myers, didn't i?
是啊 接着你就被送到了南极洲
And then you had him transferred to antarctica.
你可真谨慎啊
That's very discreet.
他说他喜欢寒冷嘛
He said he liked the cold.
我会像影子一样
Like a shadow.
像夜晚的影子一样
Like a shadow in the night.
（曼哈顿 23点37分）
美国海关发现非法进口物品
Us customs discovered a few illegally imported items.
是一些气囊 属于轻微违法物品
It's a minor infraction. and a gas pocket.
他们在那里发现些气囊
They detected a gas pocket up there.
现在联邦调查局 在我的指挥下
Now fbi agents, under my command,
正戴着防护装备上楼去了
Are going up there right now with special gas equipment.
老天 这里真臭
Jeez, it stinks in here.
这里比我的房间还乱
This is worse than my room.
在等这东西的报告
Waiting for a report on that.
说「茄子」
Say "cheese."
咱们走
Let's go.
不管他们叫我们来干什么 看来没事了
Whatever they called us for is over.
报告说这里有70多位宾客
We had over 70 guests reported.
没有生还者 也没有尸体
We have no survivors, no bodies.
这里也是 宝贝
Same story here, babe.
别叫我「宝贝」
Don't call me "babe."
我说的是「亚伯」 频道错了
"Abe, " I said."abe." wrong channel.
亚伯 我想丽兹还在生我的气
Abe, I think liz is still mad at me.
还是一样的频道
Still the same channel.
能问你个问题吗
Can I ask you a question?
不能
No.
一会儿回到家
Now, listen. When we get home later,
我会收拾我的烂摊子
I'm gonna clean up my whole mess.
不是那个问题
That's not the problem.
那是什么
What is it?
现在不是时候
Not now.
亚伯 你有什么发现
Abe, what have you got?
真有趣
Oh, this is interesting.
两个盒子都有皇家印章
Both boxes have the royal seal.
它们只在战时才生产
Only delivered at a time of war.
红大个 我们有伴了
Red? We have company.
快点 布鲁 给我点活干
Come on, blue, give me something to work with here.
洞穴生物
Burrowing creatures.
- 有多少 - 很多
- How many of them? - Many.
这里没有尸体是因为这里没有什么遗留物
There are no corpses because there are no leftovers.
注意过地板吗
Have you noticed the floor?
妈的（还有粪便之意）
Oh, crap.
对了
Precisely.
它们要做的就是不停地吃啊吃
All these things do is eat and eat.
然后排便 然后再吃
Then poop, and then eat again.
让你想起谁了吗
Remind you of anyone?
妈的 亚伯 这些是什么东西
Damn it, abe. What are these things?
说英语 说英语
English, english.
它们是牙齿仙子
Oh, they're tooth fairies.
不是 它们生活在三世纪的德国山林区
No, no. Third century, black forest.
主要以钙 骨头 皮肤和器官为食
Feed mostly on calcium, bones, skin, organs.
但它们会先吃牙齿
But they do go for the teeth first.
所以唤作嗜齿仙子
Hence the name tooth fairies.
我敢说它们也吃钱
I bet you they don't leave money, either.
天哪
Oh, my god.
丽兹 你有身孕了
Liz, you're pregnant.
没有 我没有
No, I'm not.
你有 你是有了
Yes, you are.
你那有什么发现 马博
What have you got, marble?
我想我找到了一个
Think I may have found one.
不过它看起来还算可爱
But he's kind of cute.
别靠近它
Don't go near it!
它在咬我
It's biting me!
马博
Marble.
好痛 好痛
It hurts! It hurts!
红大个 我们这需要你
Red, we need you here!
马博
Marble.
这些肮脏的小…
Nasty little…
接着开枪 亚伯 接着开枪
Keep firing, abe. Keep firing!
妈的
Damn.
抱歉 女士
Sorry, lady.
你们走开
You should be running.
楼上有保险室
There's a safe upstairs.
咱们怎么上去
How do we get there?
给我们开路
We need a clearing.
快跑
Run!
到保险室去 快
Up to the safe, now!
亚伯 上楼
Abe. Up the stairs.
快点 丽兹 烧死它们 快走 快走
Come on, liz, burn them all. Go. Go!
我们在走
Yes, we're going!
到保险室去 亚伯 到保险室去
Get in the safe, abe. Get in the safe!
不 不
Oh, no, no.
不 不 不
No, no, no!
史帝尔
Steel!
这些该死的小畜生
Damned beasts.
火由我生
Fire is mine.
我身孕火
Fire is in me.
红大个 离窗户远点
Red, stay away from the window!
火即是我
Fire is me.
别咬了
Stop biting me!
火即是我
Fire is me.
俗世 我来了
World, here I come.
你都干了什么
What have you done?
我想我们暴露了
Guess we're out.
地狱男爵 这边
Hey, hellboy, over here.
（铁路院子东边 午夜）
尊敬的殿下
Your royal highness.
努阿达王子
欢迎您归来
进入会议厅前
Before entering the council chamber,
您必须交出武器
You must surrender your weapon.
我不会交的
I will not.
殿下 无论贫富贵贱 我们一视同仁
It is protocol, sire, for peasant and prince alike.
议会长 我很荣幸可以亲手了结你
别这样 哥哥
交出武器吧
妹妹 为了你
For you, sister,
怎样都可以
Anything.
据消息灵通人士透露
According to multiple eye witnesses,
人们正出于危险之中
Lives were, in fact, endangered.
这就是地狱男爵
There you have it, hellboy.
但他是我们这边的吗
But is he really on our side?
你有超能力吗
Do you have superpowers?
有的
Well, yeah.
但我真的只想做个普通人
But, really, all I wanna be is just an ordinary person,
就像你和其他人一样
Just like you and you and everybody.
大伙 你们快错过新闻了
Hey, guys. You're missing this.
我们上电视了
We're on tv.
丽兹 丽兹 你还好吧
Liz. Liz, are you all right?
还好 我一会出来
Yeah, i'll be out in a minute.
你不用这么做 相信我
You don't need to do that. You can trust me.
我算的很准的
My readings are quite accurate.
闭嘴 亚伯
Shut up, abe.
把你的手拿开那扇门
Get your damn hand away from the door.
你什么都不用担心
You have nothing to fear.
尽管相貌并不出众
In spite of appearances,
我相信红大个会是个出色的父亲
I believe red would be an excellent father figure.
那这家伙呢
And what about this guy?
戴着个马桶座圈走来走去的
Walking around with a toilet seat on his head.
马桶座圈
A toilet seat!
很明显 这是呼吸器
It's quite obvious it's a breathing apparatus.
我想我们得丢了那辆垃圾车
Hey, I think we gotta lose the garbage truck.
它会发出错误的信号
Sends out the wrong signal.
你认为这是我们的问题
You think that's our problem?
运输吗
Transportation?
还有这个女孩
And this girl,
我们一定得找出她得了什么病
We definitely have to find out what's wrong with her.
不过她很可爱 我们应该让她上节目
She's cute, though. We should get her on the show.
我讨厌人们盯着我看
I hate it when people stare at me.
让我感觉自己跟怪胎似的
Makes me feel like a freak.
你没有权利 红大个
You had no right, red.
是曼宁 你能…
It's manning. Could you…
你要我告诉你多少次
How many times do I have to tell you?
那是气孔
It's a gas pocket.
这种现象发生在…
And a gaseous phenomenon that occurred…
气孔 真是个笨蛋
Gas pocket. What an idiot.
我被你害惨了
You've murdered me.
You have murdered me.
你还嘲弄我
You have ridiculed me.
这是你自找的
And you have brought this unto yourself.
怎么了
What?
华盛顿那边派下来一名新的BPRD干员
Washington is sending down a new bprd agent.
来新人了吗
A new guy?
为什么
Why?
是来关照你的
To look after you.
殿下 请
Sire, please.
父王
为什么？
你为什么要这么做？
为了重获自由 所有人的自由 父王
To set us free. All of us, father.
你已经破坏了古时我们同人类…
制定的的休战协定
那是用耻辱换来的休战
A truce based on shame.
人类已经忘了谁是他们的神
The humans have forgotten the gods,
它们破坏了地球 为了什么呢
Destroyed the earth. And for what?
停车场 商业街
Parking lots. Shopping malls.
他们的心已被贪婪所吞噬
Greed has burned a hole in their heart
他们的欲望永远不能满足
That will never be filled.
永不知足
They will never have enough.
人类这么做是出于天性
遵守协定是我们值得荣耀的天性
荣耀
Honor?
看看这地方 荣耀何在？
Look at this place. Where is the honor in it?
父王 你曾是个受人尊敬的勇士
Father, you were once a proud warrior.
你什么时候变成了他们的玩物
When did you become their pet?
我结束流放 回来挑起战争
I have returned from exile to wage war
来收回我们的土地 我们天赐的权利
And reclaim our land, our birthright.
为此 我会发动
And for that, I will call upon
所有的子民
The help of all of my people.
无论他们善恶与否
And they will answer,
即便是最邪恶的
The good, the bad
都会应声而起
And the worst.
黄金军团
你不是疯了吧
也许我是疯了 也许是它们让我这么做的
Perhaps I am. Perhaps they made me so.
唤醒军团…
我们的绿地也不会在鲜血中生长
让军团就这么睡去吧
如果我们的时代结束了…
我们就应该隐退
我们不会隐退的
We will not fade.
我最后一次问你 儿子
你真要这么做吗？
是的
It is.
对不起 父王
I am sorry, father.
你让我别无选择
你必须死
你呢 妹妹
And you, sister,
你赞同父王的决定吗
Are you at peace with your king's verdict?
是的 哥哥 我赞同
I am, my brother. I am.
那好吧 死就死吧
Then very well. Death it is.
我是爱你的 父亲
还有最后一块 妹妹
Now, for the final piece, my sister.
她在哪 文克 她在哪
Where is she, wink? Where is she?
去找到她 快去 找到她
Go find her. Now! Find her!
电梯已到42层
Elevator arriving now to section 42.
抱歉 大伙 借过 借过
Pardon me, boys. Excuse me. Excuse me.
- 他来了吗 - 还没
- Is he here? - Not yet.
跟你说 我们不需要这家伙
I'm telling you, we don't need this guy.
我想我们需要
Well, I think we do.
看得出 他可是
Evidently, this guy's
华盛顿那边的大人物
Quite the big shot in washington.
他叫什么名字
What's his name?
他叫乔汉·克拉斯
His name is johann krauss.
乔汉·克拉斯吗 听起来像德国人
Johann krauss? Sounds german.
在外质学方面 他可是…
He's the top man in…
巨擘
Ectoplasmic.
对 谢谢 外质学研究专家
Yes, thank you. Ectoplasmic research.
由我们的欧洲联络会强力推荐
Comes highly recommended by our european liaison.
- 乔汉·克拉斯 - 联络
- Johann krauss. - "Liaison."
我爱这个词 你不爱吗
I love that word, don't you?
真是带劲
It's so hoity toity.
- 我不喜欢德国人 - 没有指纹
- I don't like germans. - No fingerprints.
- 他来了 - 德国人让我紧张
- Here he comes. - Germans make me nervous.
没有图片 档案上有的
No photo. Dossier says,
我来翻译 他有一张受大众喜欢的脸蛋
And I translate, "he has a nice open face."
天哪
Oh, my god.
女士们 先生们 乔汉·克拉斯听候差遣
Damen und herren, johann krauss at your service.
我喜欢他
I like him.
看看这个 可怜的小东西
Look at that. Poor little thing.
在黑市被买来卖去
Bought and sold on the black market.
塞进集装箱
Crammed into cargo containers.
被走私 滥用
Smuggled, abused.
他的手可真是动作丰富啊
He has very expressive hands.
这个盒子上的印章也让我忧心
The seal on the box worries me also.
一个战争徽章
A warring emblem.
没错 来自地球之子
Yes, from the bethmoora clan.
贝茨莫拉部族的
The sons of the earth.
你的档案上说你是这的头
Your file says you're the brains of the operation,
我得承认 你确实让我眼前一亮
And I must admit, I'm impressed.
克拉斯先生 在我档案里 你会看到
In my file, you'll see, mr. Krauss,
我在亚伯的项目上和他紧密合作
That I worked very closely with abe in his training.
好的
Ja, okay.
让我们看看这位小朋友还能记起什么
Let's see what our little friend here can remember.
在你刚烧死时
Memory gets a little sketchy
记忆会有点模糊不清的
Right after you've burned to death.
但是 也许圣玛拉基能帮上忙
But maybe saint malachy can help.
不行 不行 不能用护身符
Oh, no, no. No amulets, mein herr.
电塑
Teleplasty.
塑料的 够先进
Plastic. Very modern.
跟克拉斯博士一样 是一种外质媒介
Teleplasty by which an ectoplasmic medium,
它可以控制无生命的事物
Such as dr. Krauss, can control inanimate things,
有机的 机械的 死的或者活的
Organic, mechanical, dead or alive.
吸进它 全都吸进去
Take it, take it all in, mein junge.
好了 起来吧
There we are. Get up.
起来 起来
Get up. Get up.
我现在可以完全控制它的边缘系统
Now I have full control of its limbic system.
让我们看看我能撑多久
Let us see how long I can hold it.
什么
What?
你咬掉了我尾巴尖
Hey, you chewed off the tip of my tail.
你这个小…
Yeah, you, you little…
它说你很粗鲁 野蛮 而且不是很聪明
It says you're rude, brutish und not very bright.
看来我们的小朋友
It seems our little friend here
记起了市场里的声音
Remembers market sounds and voices.
还有一种罕见的初尔语言
And a peculiar troll language spoken
它的箱子最后被打开的地方是
In the last place his cage was opened.
初尔市场
The troll market.
初尔市场 拜托
The troll market? Come on.
没人找到过它
No one's ever found it.
那是因为它并不存在
That's because it doesn't exist.
克拉斯先生 克拉斯先生
Mr. Krauss? Dr. Krauss, sir.
我们的告密人看来快不行了
Our little informant there doesn't look so good.
回来吧 好了
Back inside, you. There we are.
现在我们知道该从哪里开始了
So, now we know where to begin.
大桥下面的初尔市场
Trolls dwell under bridges.
你真是个天才
Wow. You're a genius.
顺便提一下
By the way,
纽约市可有2000多座桥
There's over 2, 000 bridges in new york city.
但19世纪的神秘主义历史学家
But vladimir vanya,
弗拉基米尔·樊亚
19th century occult historian,
就把初尔市场建在
Places the troll market directly under
布鲁克林大桥的最东端
The east end of the brooklyn bridge.
我们已经查过那了
We've already looked there.
没错 你是去过了 但当时我没去 干员
Yes, you have, but not with me, agent.
我没去
Not with me.
开始行动
We're moving in.
（布鲁克林大桥 3点30分）
往前来 往前来 停下
Keep it coming, keep it coming. Hold it.
「我没去 干员」 真是个自大狂
"Not with me, agent." what an ego.
我喜欢他
I like him.
那你跟他混吧
Well, you can keep him.
难道只有我认为
I mean, am I the only one
那家伙是个…
That thinks this guy is full of…
别 别 别 别靠上去
No, no, no, no, don't lean.
336箱 舒弗汀眼镜 难道它是
Lot 336, the schufftein glasses. Could it be?
仅存的三副
The three surviving pairs,
我们要用它们来确定初尔市场的位置
And we will use them to locate the troll market.
克拉斯博士 真有你的
Dr. Krauss, what a coup.
舒弗汀眼镜
The schufftein glasses.
崇拜死你了
You're my hero.
你是地狱男爵吗
Hey. You hellboy?
对
Yeah.
哥们儿 你长得可真丑
You're ugly, man.
在我前面的墙上再放两个
Two more on the wall in front of me
然后在巷子里放三个 朝着那条路
And then three on the alleys facing that way.
你觉得那位「万事通」先生怎么样
What do you think of mr. know-lt-all?
我不知道 现在下结论为时过早
Don't know, too early to tell.
你就是地狱男爵
Hey, you're hellboy.
我知道 我很丑
I know, I'm ugly.
算你有自知之明
Forget it.
我们迟些再聊
We'll talk about it later.
他对自己很自信
He's sure of himself
我想你可能觉得自己受到威胁了
And I think maybe you're intimidated.
受到威胁？
Intimidated. huh?
保持监视器信号
Keep us up to date on the cameras,
谢尔曼探员 完毕
Agent sherman. over and out.
这是什么
What's this?
平常我们看不到小精灵和巨魔
Normally, we can't see fairy folk and trolls.
他们能产生一种叫「魔环」的光环
They generate a cloaking aura
包裹住自己
Called "glamour."
但在1878年 埃米尔·舒弗汀
But in 1878, emil schufftein
设计并制作了这些
Designed and built these.
四组水晶屈光镜可以穿透那种效果
Four crystal diopters that penetrate that effect
看到事物的本质
And reveal the true nature of things.
克拉斯博士 它比我想的还美
Oh, dr. krauss, they're more beautiful than I'd imagined.
你戴上试试
You must try them on then. oh, yes.
戴上试试 探员 一定很帅
Try them on, agent. they'll look good.
我喜欢这种紧凑的小皮带
I love these tight little leather straps.
受到威胁？
Intimidated?
克劳特 先生
Mr. kraut? sir?
克拉斯 探员 两个'S'
Krauss, agent. with a double "s."
两个S 对…
S-s. right, right.
听着 这些小发明
Listen, those gizmos?
你怎么知道它有效
How do you know they work?
我发现一个疑犯
I have a suspect.
告诉我坐标 谢尔曼探员 坐标
Give me a vector, agent sherman. a vector.
B12 小巷子里 往北
B-12, the alley, northbound.
好 盯住他 我们马上到
Well, track the target. we're coming down.
看好他 我马上回来
Keep an eye on her. I'll be right back.
这个小老太太 得了吧
This little old lady? come on.
那是一种丑陋的苏格兰巨魔
It's a fragglewump, an ugly scottish troll.
它们怕金丝雀
They're afraid of canaries.
我的天啊 金丝雀
Oh, my god. canaries, huh?
那些小猫呢
What about the kittens?
她吃它们
She feeds on them.
过来 小猫们
Come on, then. kitty, kitty, kitty.
那也能叫她
That thing is a "she"?
（布鲁克林大桥下方 4点57分）
趴下 蠢货
Down, you fools.
你在干嘛
What do you think you are doing?
她要吃那猫
She's gonna eat the cat.
你会让她发现我们的
You'll make her aware of our presence.
我们现在该用金丝雀
We should use the canary now.
她就要吃了
She's gonna eat it!
我们该用这只鸟了 克拉斯博士
We should use the bird, dr. krauss.
这个金丝雀
The bird.
她要吃了
She's going to eat the cat.
你们不得行动 必须听我的命令
You will stay put and follow my orders.
我不能光看着…
I can't sit by here…
你受我直接领导 必须服从我的命令
You are directly under my command, and you have to obey.
- 呆着别动 - 滚吧
- Stay put! - Oh, screw this!
嘿 露西
Hey! lucy.
快回来
Come back here.
我来了
I'm home.
亲爱的 我能帮你什么吗
Oh, yes, dearie. can I help you?
别装了 脏东西 我们能看穿你
Give it up, nasty. we can see you.
看穿我
You see me?
怎么会 你们怎么会看穿我
How? how do you see me?
我们在寻找去初尔市场的入口 你知道吗
We're looking for the entrance to the troll market. any clues?
再靠近我就把你的心挖出来
Come any closer and I'll rip your heart.
我们得用老办法了 亚比
We're gonna have to get a little old-school, abe.
把鸟给我
Give me the bird.
不要啊 我怕金丝雀
Not a canary.
什么 你怕这个小家伙
What, you're afraid of this little guy?
你们知道吗
Who'd know?
够了 够了
No more, no more.
我带你们去
I'll take you there.
来吧 我们走 你这又老又脏的巨魔
Come on, let's go, you dirty old troll.
我们走
Let's go.
谢尔曼探员 我们正往初尔市场去
Agent sherman, we are going into the troll market.
保持最低限度的联络 完毕
Keep communication to a minimum.Over und out.
我喜欢他
I like him.
看看 这才是做领导的人
You see, this is a man who takes charge.
你真这么认为吗
You think?
是的 他很能干
Yeah. he's efficient.
做事明确
He's precise.
要确定他的抵抗力 你得多注意他
You add "resistant" to that, you got yourself a new watch.
克拉斯博士被命令所约束 但是他…
Dr. krauss is aware of the chain of command, and he…
哦 老兄
Oh, brother!
他看上去和我一样
He seems to like me.
我们到了
Here we are.
哇 真是座大门
Wow, that's some door!
这是一种复杂的密码锁
It's a complex combination lock.
你觉得如何 西皮恩探员
What do you think, agent sapien?
不妙
Not good.
从密码符号的数量看
With the number of symbols on the combination,
我们得花上几天时间
We'll be here for days.
没有必要
Well, not necessarily.
让我试试我的技术
Let me try my technique.
打开它 露西
Open it, lucy.
我才不
I will not.
看看这个小可爱
Pretty please.
恶魔 随你便吧
Do as you may, demon.
把这个黄色怪物放出来
Release the yellow beast.
挖我的眼
Tear my eyes out.
破我的肚 断我的腿 割我的舌
Rip my insides and my legs and my tongue,
但我永远不会打开这扇门
But I will never open that door.
这就是你的调查技术吗
Is that your investigative technique?
它说永远不
It said "never."
真过分
It's unconscionable.
这说明他不喜欢这种方式
That means he didn't like it.
什么
What?
那么你要给我们表演怎么开吗
So, what, you're gonna show us how it's done,
老教条先生
Mr. by-the-book?
是这样吗
Is that it?
是的 我想是的
Yes, I think I will.
我们开始吧
There we are.
让我来看看 对了
Let me see. yes.
先生们 欢迎来到初尔市场
Gentlemen, welcome to the troll market.
鲜鱼
来买鲜鱼
红大个 有件很重要的事
Liz.' red, there's something really important
我得告诉你
That I need to tell you.
哦 丽兹 你应该来的 你会喜欢这里的
Oh, liz, you should be here. you'd love it.
没人注意我们 我们就这么混进来了
Nobody's looking at us. we blend right in.
探员 我说过保持最低限度的通讯
Agent, I said keep communication to a minimum.
你会暴露我们的身份的
You'll blow our cover.
你知道吗 我觉得他说的对
You know? I think he's right.
我会带你来的 宝贝儿
I'm bringing you here for sure, babe.
那个鱼碗要求无线电静默 所以…
The fishbowl wants radio silence. so…
结束吧
Over and out.
皇室印章
The royal seal.
红大个兄弟 红大个 能听到吗
Brother red. red, do you read me?
是的 能听到 我正看大侦探在工作呢
Yeah, I read you, blue, but I'm watching sherlock at work.
我一会儿和你汇合
I'll get back to you.
打搅一下 先生
Excuse me, sir.
先生 对不起 先生 我能问一个…
Sir, excuse… pardon me. sir, may I ask a…
我得告诉孩子们这件事
I gotta tell the boys that one.
打搅一下 先生
Excuse me, gentlemen.
你们看到过有人买这种嗜齿妖吗
Have you seen anyone purchasing this type of tooth fairy?
这儿没人卖这些 伙计
No one sells them down here, pal.
也许在泽西有
Over in jersey, maybe.
那么这个呢
Well, what about this, then?
你们认识这个印章吗
Do you recognize this seal?
叫他走 叫他走
Make him go away. make him go away.
不 没见过
No. we don't.
求你了 亲爱的先生
Please, dear sir.
你最好马上走
You'd better go. now!
你们开个价吧
We'll make it worth your while.
你别浪费时间了 我们不会说的
Don't waste your time. we will not talk!
你在干什么
What are you doing?
你确定你知道吗
You're absolutely sure about that, huh?
当然
Absolutely.
你不会说是吗
You won't talk, eh?
永远不说
Never.
永远不
Never, huh?
永永远远不
Never ever, ever.
现在有点想谈了吗
Feeling a little chattier now?
我们永远都不会说
We'll never talk.
我愿意说…
Yes, yes.
我说 只是别再打我了
We will, only don't hit me anymore.
胆小鬼
Chicken.
谁买了那些嗜齿妖
Who bought the tooth fairies?
努阿达王子
Prince nuada.
他们说努阿达王子打破了停战协定
They say prince nuada broke the truce,
现在有流言说战争将起
And now there is talk of war,
一场针对人类的战争
A war with the human world.
对不起 小鬼
Sorry, kid.
没关系
That's all right.
可爱的小宝宝
Nice baby.
我不是宝宝 我是个肿瘤
I'm not a baby. I'm a tumor.
是的 红大个 我正在跟踪
Yes, red. I am following a lead right now.
也许结果…
It may turn out…
也许没什么结果
It may turn out to be nothing,
但我会及时通知你
But I will let you know soon enough.
你要什么 报上名来
What do you want? tell me your name.
随我来
Follow me.
你父亲留给你这张地图
Your father left you this map.
他说 藏在里面的
In it, he said, lies the secret
就是黄金军团藏身地的秘密
To the location of the golden army.
快走 快 公主殿下
Move away! quickly, your highness.
需要我帮忙吗
Can I help you with something?
不 谢谢 我只是随便看看
No, thank you. I'm just looking.
你不可以进去
You can't go in there!
先生 为什么跟踪我
Sir, why are you following me?
我…
I…
我只是想找一张老的阿尔及尔的路海图
I was just hoping to find an old map chart of algiers.
你为什么跟踪我
Why are you following me?
我没有
I was not.
是我哥哥派你来偷皇冠碎片的吗
Did my brother send you to steal the crown piece?
你哥哥
Your brother?
我想你弄错了 我向你保证
Oh, you're sorely mistaken, I assure you.
那就告诉我实话
Then answer me truthfully.
你为什么跟踪我
Why were you following me?
我叫亚伯拉罕·西皮恩
My name is abraham sapien.
根本就没这种名字
There is no such name.
我也不喜欢这名字 但我…
Oh, I don't like it either, but i…
够了
Enough.
把手给我
Give me your hand.
你的手
Your hand.
你是个探员
You are an agent
为超自然现象研究防御中心工作
For the bureau of paranormal research and defense.
你的名字是…
And your name is…
很糟糕 我知道
Horrible, I know.
我是努阿拉公主
I'm nuala, princess nuala.
是的 我知道
Yes, I know.
原谅我 公主殿下
Forgive me, your highness,
在你读我的信息的时候
But as you were learning about me,
我忍不住也读了一些你的信息
I couldn't help but learn a bit about you myself.
我知道你需要我们的帮助
I know that you need our help.
我恐怕这是唯一可以走的路了
I'm afraid it's the other way around.
窗户 快出去
The window. out now.
我来应付这个家伙
I will take care of this.
哦 惨了
Oh, dear.
走 快走
Go! now go!
蓝皮 你先走
Get out of here, blue.
是 跟我来 公主殿下
Yes. come with me, your highness.
你
You.
让我做得尽量优雅点吧
Let me put this to you as delicately as I can.
我的雪茄 那可是古巴雪茄
My cigar, it was cuban.
你现在把我惹火了
Now you pissed me off.
废物
Oh, crap.
现在老实了
Now stay down!
妈的
Damn.
一颗牙齿 你开心啦
A tooth. happy?
投降吧 伙计 结束了
Give it up, pal. it's over.
我要是你可不会这么做
I wouldn't do that if I were you.
告诉过你了
Wow. told you.
天哪 你干了什么 地狱男爵
Oh, my god, what have you done, agent hellboy?
看看这个 现在我们不得不走了
Look at this! now we have to leave.
红大个 这是努阿拉公主
Red. this is princess nuala.
女士
Lady.
我们得走了 快
We should leave. now. now!
走吧
Let's go.
文克死了
一个巨大的红人杀了他
你有什么想告诉我的吗？
在那儿 不 在那儿 在市场上
文克死了
要发动战争 我哥哥需要这个
To wage his war, my brother needs this,
贝茨莫拉王冠的最后一片
The final piece of the crown of bethmoora
还有这张黄金军团藏身地的地图
And this map to the location of the golden army chamber.
黄金军团
The golden army.
死亡预兆
The harbingers of death.
势不可挡
The unstoppable tide.
倒想见识见识
Howdy doody.
殿下 如果你把皇冠的碎片交给我们…
Your highness, if you hand the crown piece over to us…
不 它去哪儿 我就去哪儿
No. where it goes, I go.
我父王因坚持与你们世界的停战协定而死
My father died to uphold the truce with your world.
你们必须尊重他高贵的意图
You must honor his noble intention.
公主正处于极度的危险
The lady's in dire danger.
你是在为公主担保吗 西皮恩探员
I take it you're vouching for her, agent sapien?
是的 我是在为她担保
Most emphatically. yes, I am.
既便如此
Even so.
我还是要说抱歉 我们不能
I am sorry, but we simply cannot assume
这么轻易地将这样的责任揽到自己身上
Such responsibility on our own.
公主刚刚失去了父亲
The lady just lost her father.
你还想怎么样
What more do you want?
也许你不在乎 但我们有自己的程序原则
You may not care, but there are procedures, rules
还有小手册…
And little handbooks…
你会和我们一起走
She's coming with us.
你听到了吗 气泡
You got that, gas bag?
你叫我什么
What did you call me?
你们
You.
会为对我朋友所做的一切付出代价
You will pay for what happened to my friend down there.
哦 是吗 你收支票吗
Yeah, right. you take checks?
恶魔
Demon.
诞生于黑影之中
Born from a womb of shadows.
被送来摧毁这个世界
Sent to destroy their world
你还以为你属于它吗
And you still believe you belong.
我们要秉烛夜谈吗
Are we gonna talk all night?
因为我真的有点困了
Cause I'm really sleepy.
不 哥哥 不
No, brother, no!
杀了他
Kill him.
只是个会跳的豆子
It's just a jumping bean.
它在找水 快点
It's going for water. hurry.
不
No. no, no, no, no. no.
那是什么
What the hell is that? excuse me!
- 别过去 - 出什么事了
- Stay back. - Hey, what's going on?
我们看到目标了
We've got target in sight.
这是个元素精灵
It's an elemental,
生命的给予者 也是破坏者
A giver of life and a destroyer.
什么
What?
森林之神
A forest god.
A forest god, eh?
我会给他好看
I'm gonna get me big baby.
救命 我的孩子 救命
Somebody help! my baby's… help! help!
需要帮忙吗 夫人
How can I help you, ma'am?
我的孩子还在车里
My baby's inside!
请跟我们走 女士
Come with us, dear lady, please.
别担心
There's nothing to worry about.
我们会处理好的
We've got everything under control.
求你了 我的孩子还在那里
Please. my baby's still in there! please!
小朋友
Hey, little guy.
靠近目标
Hoing in on target.
坚持住 小朋友
Hang on, kid.
地狱男爵
Agent hellboy.
到高处用武器射击
Reach higher ground and shoot the weapon.
用武器射击
Shoot the weapon!
先呆在我尾巴上 小朋友
First praise the tail, kid.
你必须射他的能量源
You must shoot it in the energy ganglion.
什么
The what?
能量源
The energy ganglion.
打它的脑袋
Scheisse. the head! shoot it in the head!
该死
Oh, crap.
你得信任我 小伙计
You gotta trust me, little buddy. okay?
你把孩子吵醒了
You woke up the baby.
地狱男爵 现在射击
Agent hellboy, take the shot!
快点射击
Right now! take it!
这是命令 射击
That's an order! take the shot.
这是命令
That's an order, agent hellboy.
快开枪
Shoot it! shoot the gun! shoot the gun!
恶魔
Demon.
你在等什么
What are you waiting for?
这就是你想要的 不是吗
This is what you wanted, isn't it?
看看它 它是种族里最后一个了
Look at it. it's the last of its kind.
就像你和我 如果你毁了它
Like you and I. you destroy it,
那么世界上再也不会看到这种生物了
The world will never see its like again.
开枪
Shoot it!
比起他们 你和我们有更多共同点
You have more in common with us than with them.
它开始动了
It's breaking free.
你可以成为王
You could be a king.
你不会抗命
You will not disobey a direct order!
开枪 它又动起来了
Shoot it! it's getting loose!
如果你听命令…
If you cannot command…
它会毁掉一切的
It will destroy everything!
这是命令 地狱男爵
That's an order, agent hellboy!
那么你必须服从
Then you must obey.
快开枪 该死
Shoot it now! damn.
开枪
Shoot it!
退后 退后
Move back. step back, step back.
多漂亮啊
It's beautiful.
这怪物不知从哪里冒出来
And this huge monster just came out of nowhere!
把孩子还回去
Yo, give the baby back, man!
你对我孩子做了什么
Oh, what have you done to my baby?
孩子没事
The baby's fine.
你个怪物
You freak!
地狱男爵 你对孩子做了什么
Hellboy, what'd you do to that baby?
孩子没事
The baby's fine.
别动 举起手来
Don't move. hands in the air! up!
他手里有武器
He's got a weapon in his hand.
那就是他的手
That is his hand.
小姐 请离他远点
Miss, stay away from him for your own safety.
他在努力帮忙 你们看不出来吗
He was trying to help. don't you see?
他只是想帮忙
He was just trying to help.
这就是我们所做的
That's all we do.
这就是我们这么多年来所做的
That's all we've done all these years.
她在摸他的手
She's touching his hand!
我们只是想帮你们 你们
We've just tried to help you. you.
你个怪物
You're a goddamn freak.
我们不需要你们
We don't need you around!
怪物
What a freak.
丽兹
Liz.
我们回家
Let's go home.
展开对BPRD
…Investigation of the bprd
和其中内部关系的调查
And its prootion of intra-species arriage
它们被视为传统物种的威胁
Seen by any as a threat to traditional failies,
调查由联邦出资
Fuelled by federal funds.
我还没碰到你呢
I didn't touch you yet.
你今天做得真漂亮
You did a good job out there.
那告诉我为什么我感觉这么差
Then tell me, why don't I feel so good?
我杀了那东西 为了什么呢
I mean, I killed that thing. and for what?
没人喜欢我
They don't even like me.
他们还怕我
I mean, they're afraid of me.
我们该怎么做
What do we do with that?
我不想让你担心
Red, I don't want you to freak out.
我想离开一会儿
I'm gonna leave for a little bit.
我需要时间好好想想
I need time to think.
想什么
About what?
怎么就不能在这儿想
Can't you do your thinking right here?
我会很安静的
Look, I'll be really, really quiet.
我会把猫处理好
I'll get rid of the cats.
你为什么和我在一起
Red, why are you with me?
你需要别人都喜欢你吗
Do you need everyone to like you?
每个人 或只要我喜欢就够了
Everybody? or am I enough?
想想吧
Think about it.
留下来 我们属于死亡
You stay. we belong dead.
一片空白 没坐标图
It's blank. no coordinates.
「请来我身边 当我年已暮
"Be near me when my light is low.
血气已衰落 神经在刺痛
When the blood creeps and the nerves prick and tingle.
当我心感到沉重 当生命的机能已麻木
And the heart is sick and all the wheels of being slow.
请来我身边 当我的感官
Be near me when the sensuous frame.
为压倒信心的痛楚所苦
Is wracked with pangs that conquer trust.
而时光像狂徒乱撒尘土…「
And time, a maniac…"
坦尼森的《悼念》是一首好诗
Tennyson, "in memoriam." a beautiful poem.
原谅我 我不想打断你
Forgive me, I didn't mean to startle you.
没事 我想借这本书
Oh, no. no, no. I borrowed this book.
我希望你不介意
I hope you don't mind.
当然不介意 现在这儿就是你的家
Oh, no, no. please, this is your home now.
你在这很安全
You are safe here.
我哥哥总会找到我的
My brother will find me. he always does.
他怎么会
How could he?
我们所处的位置是高度机密
Our location is a highly classified secret.
是的 但我知道 这意味着他也知道
Yes, but I know of it now, which means that he does, too.
我们是双胞胎
We're twins.
小时候 我们之间就有某种联系
Even as children, a link has bound us one to the other.
我没法解释
Something I cannot explain.
不必解释
No need.
你看起来不一样了
You look different.
有吗
Oh, do i?
也许是我的发型
Perhaps my hair?
不
No.
你的眼睛 我能看到你的眼睛了
It's your eyes. I can see your eyes.
是的 只是想换个新造型
Yes. just trying a new look.
这是地图吗
Is that a map?
是的 在圆筒里装着
Yes, it was in the cylinder.
上面没有坐标
There are no coordinates.
也许上面有浮水印
Perhaps there's a watermark.
你非常勇敢 为我担保
You were very brave vouching for me.
你怎么知道我不是敌人派来的
How do you know I'm not the enemy, bringing me here?
正如你刚才所说的
It's as you were saying just now.
通过直觉 或许 一种联系
From intuition maybe, a link.
平常我可以很快地读出这
Normally I'm able to read others quite quickly,
但我从没遇到像你一样的人
But I've never met anyone like you.
我也没遇到过像你一样的人
Nor i, like you.
晚安 亚伯拉罕
Good night, Abraham.
晚安 公主殿下
Good night, princess. your highness.
夫人…
Your majesty. your… ma'am.
夫人
Ma'am?
晚上好 地狱男爵
Gute nacht, agent hellboy.
听着 我知道你不喜欢我
Look, agent, I know you don't like me,
但我可以拿走你佩的徽章
But I could take away your badge.
从来没那玩意
Never had one.
继续问
Kept asking, though.
你要学会服从我 遵守规则
You will learn to obey me, follow protocol
并且随时保持春醒
And stay fockused at all times.
是清醒吧
Oh, that word "fockused."
那是你的口音 我才不会那么说话
Yeah, with your accent, I wouldn't use it that much.
我认识 布鲁姆教授
I knew professor Broom, young man.
你不认识
You didn't know professor broom.
我认识
Yes, I did.
- 我出事后 - 闭嘴
- After my accident… - Shut up. shut up.
…他设计了我这身衣服
…He designed this containment suit.
一位极好的人
A wonderful man.
即使如此他还是对你的未来非常担心
And even then he was worried about your future. he…
闭嘴
Hey, gas bag, stop it!
马上闭嘴
Right now.
不然怎样 你在威胁我
Or what? are you threatening me?
我认为我可以打败你
Because I think I can take you.
你说什么
Excuse me?
你听到了
You heard me.
我听不清 从那么远的地方
I couldn't hear you from all the way over there.
我能打败你 因为你有一个致命的缺点
I can take you because you have one fatal flaw.
我倒想听听看
Oh, I wanna hear it.
不 你根本听不进去
No, you don't. you can't take criticism.
试试看
Try me.
你听不进去
Can't take it.
我的缺点是什么
What's my flaw?
你的脾气 它掩盖你的优点
Your temper. it gets the best of you.
让你变弱 变脆弱
Makes you weak. makes you vulnerable.
该死
Oh, crap.
乔汉
Johann.
乔汉 乔汉
Johann? johann?
乔汉
Hey, johann?
别扯了 老兄 坚持住 好吗
Come on, pal. hang in there, will you?
乔汉 乔汉
Johann? johann?
该死
Damn.
到此为止
There we are.
你的脾气 让你变得脆弱
Your temper, it makes you sloppy.
努力控制它吧 地狱男爵
Try to control it, agent hellboy.
在它控制你之前
Before it controls you.
混球
Glasshole.
你好 红大个
Hello, red.
你来晚了
Well, you're up late.
你在听什么
What are you listening to?
维瓦尔第 阿尔莫尼亚西门托
Vivaldi. il ciento dell'aronia.
我尤其喜欢最后那段…
I particularly like the last…
那是什么
Hey, hey. what's that?
遥控器
Just a remote.
这个
This? yes.
「流行情歌」
"Popular love songs."
亚伯
Oh, abe.
你爱上公主了
You fell for the princess.
她… 她和我一样
She's… she's like me.
是另一个世界的生物
A creature from another world.
再多说点
You need to get out more.
她在世上很孤单 我想帮她
She's alone in the world. I wanna help her.
我得关心她
I need to care for her.
你恋爱了 来罐啤酒
You're in love. have a beer.
不 我的身体是座寺庙
Oh, my body's a temple.
现在是游乐场啦
Well, now it's an amusement park.
不
No, no, no.
我的腺体平衡…
The glandular balance of…
别废话 喝了 好吗
Just shut up and drink it, would you?
- 哪一首 - 第八首
- What track? - Eight.
《没有你的悲伤》
Can't smile without you.
我知道
I know.
我也得来罐啤酒
Yep, I'm gonna need a beer, too.
你瞧 我爱这首歌
Well, see, I love this song.
而且我不能哭或笑
And I can't smile or cry.
我想我没有泪腺
I think I have no tear ducts.
我真希望老爸在
I wish father were here.
他知道怎么跟你说 跟我们说
He'd know what to tell you. us.
没有你无法微笑
I can't smile without you
我不能笑 也不能唱
I can't laugh and I can't sing
做什么事都很难
I' finding it hard to do anything
你看 你难过时我也难过
You see, I feel sad when you're sad
你高兴时我也高兴
I feel glad when you're glad
多希望你了解我的心情
If you only knew what I' going through
没有你无法微笑
I just can't smile without you
你飘过
You came along
就像一首歌
Just like a song
给我光亮
And brightened my day
似梦非梦
Who'd have believed that you were part of a dream?
时光已逝
Now it all sees light years away
没有你无法微笑
And now you know I can't sile without you
I can't smile without you
努阿拉
Nuala.
他来了
狗狗真乖
Good dog.
禀告前门的安全情况
Security detail for the front gate, immediately.
最后一打了
It's the last one.
看看她 她就是 亚伯
Look at her. she's it, Abe.
她就是
She's it.
她是我生命的全部…
She's my whole wide…
你知道吗
You know?
知道
Yeah. yeah.
我愿为她献出生命
I would give my life for her.
但她也想让我洗碗
But she also wants me to do the dishes.
我愿做任何事
I would die and do the dishes.
她为啥生我的气
Why is she mad at me?
不是因为房间脏
It's not because the room is dirty.
是别的
Something else.
那就问她
Well, ask her, then.
不
No.
听着 亚伯
Listen, Abe.
好的
Yeah.
当女人为某件事生气的时候
When a woman's mad about something,
其实她是为了别的生气
But she's really mad about something else,
你不可以问 她们会因你不知道而生气
You can't ask because then
她们会因你后知后觉而生气
They get angry because you had to ask.
你明白我的意思吗
Do you know what I mean?
算了 别回答了
Never mind, don't answer that question.
你得…
You gotta just…
是啊
Yeah.
自己找出答案
Find out.
你动作真快 羊皮纸
Very quick of you. the parchment.
没什么用
It was of no importance.
圆筒却很有趣
The cylinder is very interesting.
我们会在这里找到黄金军团
We will find the golden army here.
至于皇冠的碎片 我知道它就在这
As for the crown piece, I know it's here.
我可以通过你感觉到
I can feel that much from you.
父王总是费尽心机把你我的心分隔开
Father always tried so hard to shield your heart from mine.
碎片就在某本书里 我会找出来的
But it's in one of the books, and I will find it.
蓝色
Blue.
你穿蓝色总是特别漂亮
You always look so beautiful in blue.
蓝色
Blue.
诗歌 爱情
Poetry. love.
得而复失
"Found then lost."
无论如何 我会找出来的
Only words. I will find it.
听着 红大个
Listen, listen, Red.
我知道丽兹怎么了
I know what's going on with Liz.
红大个
Red.
亚伯
Abe.
抱歉 他必须知道
I'm sorry. he has to know.
亚伯
Abe!
知道什么
Know what?
为什么
Why?
退后 我先进去
Stay back. I'll go first.
亚伯拉罕 别过来 他会杀了你
Abraham. no, don't… he'll kill you.
公主
Princess?
亚伯拉罕
Abraham?
你那样叫他？
不
No!
我会杀了你 亚伯拉罕
I will kill you, Abraham.
或者其他任何人
And anyone else if that is necessary.
好吧
Well?
为什么你不从我开始 混蛋殿下
Then why don't you just start with me, your royal assness?
这是谁放的
Who put those there?
你空着手就想跟我打
And your weapon of choice?
要收拾你 五根手指还嫌多呢
Five-fingered mary.
你动一下我就杀了亚伯拉罕
You move and I'll kill your Abraham first.
红大个 你绝不能伤了王子
Red, you mustn't harm the prince.
什么
What?
伤了他 公主也会受伤
If you hurt him, you hurt the princess.
开什么玩笑
You've gotta be kidding me.
给我皇冠的碎片
Will you give me the crown piece?
不
No.
- 碎片 - 不
- The piece. - No.
亚伯
Abe?
抱歉 红大个 但他们命运相连
Red, I'm so sorry, but they're linked.
怎么回事
What's going on?
- 红大个 - 丽兹
- Red. - Liz.
红大个 小心后面
Red, behind you.
过去你可曾想过「我终将面对死亡吗」
You may have mused in the past, "am I mortal?"
现在就是了
You are now.
亚伯拉罕 许多人为了皇冠而死
Abraham, many people have died for this crown.
他也不例外
He will, too.
若你想救他 并再见到她
If you want to save him and see her again,
就找出遗失的皇冠碎片 带来给我
You will find the missing piece and bring it to me.
天啊 亚伯 快把这该死的东西拔出来
Jesus, Abe, pull the damn thing out!
不行
I cannot.
每次我一靠近它 一碰它
Every time I touch it, every time I come close to it,
它就更深地刺向他的心脏
It moves closer to his heart.
我无计可施
I don't know what else to do.
除非拔掉矛尖 不然伤口无法愈合
The wound will not heal until the spear is removed.
没时间了
We're running out of time.
那我们去找王子
Then we go after the prince.
逼他把矛尖拿出来
And we make him take it out.
嘿 丽兹
Hey, Liz.
你那时问我
You were asking me.
别说话
Don't talk.
不 不 让我说
No, no, let me tell you.
我知道什么对我来说重要
I know what's important.
是你
It's you.
红大个
Red.
我可以不管全世界 不顾一切
I could turn my back on the world, all of it,
只要你和我在一起
As long as you stay with me.
我会的
I'll stay with you.
你是我遇过最好的人
You're the best man I've ever met.
「人」吗
"Man."
努阿拉 「请来我身边 当我年已暮」
Nuala."Be near and when light is low."
“血气已衰落…
"When the blood creeps…
当我心感到沉重 当生命的机能已麻木”
And the heart is sick and all the wheels of being slow"
圆筒上的坐标指向
The cylinder yielded coordinates
位于爱尔兰北部安特里姆郡的
To county Antrim, northern ireland.
大堤道 就是这儿了
The giant's causeway. right about here.
很好 知道他在哪儿了
Great. so we know where he is.
那还等什么呢
What are we waiting for?
该上路了
We should get going.
谢尔曼探员 王子要皇冠的碎片
The prince will demand the crown piece, agent sherman.
那又如何 我们给他
So we give it to him.
曼宁博士
Dr. Manning?
事情恐怕没这么简单
I'm afraid it's not as simple as that.
等等 你是什么意思
Hold on here, what are you saying?
绝不能唤醒黄金军团
The golden army must not awaken.
那又怎样
So, what?
你们就眼睁睁看着他死 是吗
You're just gonna let him die, is that it?
很遗憾
I'm sorry.
我们禀告了华盛顿当局 只能听命行事
We called Washington. we have our orders.
你也这么想吗 他救过你一命
And what about you? he saved your life.
我知道
I know.
我知道你很难接受 但…
I know this is difficult for you, but…
随便你 我不会让他死的
Well, I won't let him die.
谢尔曼探员 我要提醒你
Agent sherman, may I remind you
我才是指挥官
That I am the leader of this team.
那毋庸置疑 长官
Oh, there's no doubt about that, sir.
这就是你 克拉斯博士
That is what you are, Dr. Krauss.
即使你曾是人类 那也是很久以前的事了
And if ever you were human, that time is long gone.
她吃错了什么药
What's wrong with her?
要我叫她回来吗 长官
You want me to call her back, sir?
算了
Let her go.
我能理解
I understand.
你呢
What about you?
找到什么了
You find anything?
没有 目前还没
No. nothing yet.
那就继续找
Well, keep looking.
当然 长官
Absolutely, sir.
全部都去找
All of you.
别担心长官 碎片在这里 我们会找到的
But don't worry, sir, we know it's here, and we're gonna find it.
没有汤姆·曼宁办不成的事
When Tom Manning gets on the case, things get done.
事情说成 就得成
They get done. they get done!
我说到做到
100. I guarantee that.
即使没有碎片 也要把他带离这里
Even without the piece, we have to get him out of here.
我们去安特里姆郡找王子
We'll go to Antrim, and we will find the prince.
继续找
Keep looking.
每个人都去找
I ask you, everybody, keep looking.
亚伯
Abe.
就我们俩
Just the two of us.
好 好
Yes. yes.
走吧
Let's go.
现在就得走 趁他们还没找到楼上前走
We need to leave now, before they run our clearance upstairs.
晚上好啊[德语]
Guten abend, eine freunde.
有人批准你们把飞机开走吗
Do you have authorization to take that plane?
乔汉 你阻止不了我们
You're not gonna stop us, Johann.
正好相反 我想过了
On the contrary, I've been giving it some thought,
应该有办法救地狱男爵
And we should be able to save agent hellboy.
你说我不是人类了 但你错了
You say I'm not human anymore, but you are wrong.
我非常能理解你的痛苦
I understand your pain all too well.
很久以前 我失去了我挚爱的女人
A long time ago, I lost the woman I loved.
而那也是我变成现在这副悲惨模样的源头
And that was, in fact, the source of my present misfortune.
将来我会告诉你们
I will tell you about it one day.
但现在 我们较占优势
But for now, the tactical advantage is ours.
试想下 王子的皇冠少了一块
Consider this, the prince lacks the crown piece
皇冠不全 他的军团就没有威胁
And without it, his army poses no threat.
那我们得到批准了吗
So we have clearance, then?
去他妈的批准 谢尔曼·丽兹探员
Agent Sherman Liz, screw the clearance.
我们去开飞机
We will take that plane!
（安特里姆郡 北爱尔兰 9点）
应该就在这儿
It should be here someplace.
入口应该就在这儿
The entrance should be here.
我不明白
I don't understand.
也许地图有错
Perhaps there's a mistake on the map.
你们好
Hello there!
欢迎你们 陌生人
I bid you welcome, strangers.
有什么我能帮忙的呢
How can I be of assistance?
我们在找通向贝茨莫拉的安全道路
We seek safe passage to Bethmoora.
你这样的人儿为何想去那种地方
And what does a nice little girl like you want in the nightlands?
我们要找努阿达王子
We are looking for prince Nuada.
是他啊 我明白了
Him, I know.
给我点东西作为交换 就带你们去找他
Trade me something, and I'll take you to him.
这儿 我有条亮闪闪的腰带
Here. I have a shiny belt.
可我又没有裤子
But I have no pants.
瞧 一副奇妙的魔术眼
Look, a wonderful set of magic eyes.
我已经有望远镜了
I already have binoculars.
不过我看到些特别的
But I see something special,
那绷带下发亮的东西
something shiny underneath the bandages.
我要那个
I want that.
这个不行
No, you can't take it out.
拔出来他会死的
Not without killing him.
也许我认识的某人可以
Maybe I know someone who can.
到时你会跟我换吗
Will you trade me then?
好吧
All right.
非常好
Very well.
继续走 继续走
Keep going. keep going.
天哪
Oh, my god.
你们真该看看这座城市昔日的样貌
You should have seen this city when it was alive.
为什么会变成这样
What happened to it?
诅咒
Curse.
自从黄金军团在这里驻扎
As soon as the golden army was stored here,
灾祸 寂静和死亡就落在我们头上
A plague of silence and death befell us.
世界也抛弃了我们
And the world left us behind.
很长一段时间 我独居在这片废墟中
For a long time, I alone dwelled in the dust.
好啦 小女孩 你们俩进来
All right, little girl, the two of you come inside.
剩下的在外头等
The rest of you, wait out here.
你好啊 朋友
Hello, old friend.
我给你带了几位客人
I have brought you visitors.
我想请你帮个忙
And I have a favor to ask you.
小妖精 我可不想帮你忙 走吧
I owe no favor to you, Goblin. leave.
可我给你做了多少事啊
But I have done so much for you.
我给你带了好多纪念品
I have brought you many souvenirs.
而且他身上有亮闪闪的东西
And he has something shiny.
红大个
Red.
属于我的
Something mine.
红大个
Red!
阿努·恩·拉玛
Anung un rama.
你知道这名字
You know that name?
还有你 伊莉莎白·谢尔曼
And yours. Elizabeth Sherman.
最终你们还是来了
At last.
我等你们好久了
I have been waiting for you both many a winter moon.
我是他的死亡
I am his death,
在命运的交叉点 我们会相遇
And I will meet him at each crossroads.
好 但那东西什么时候能归我
Good. but when can I have that which is mine?
你能救他吗
Can you save him?
决定在你
It is for you to decide that.
世事于我皆无不同
It is all the same to me.
我的心早已尽是灰土与沙砾
My heart is filled with dust and sand,
但是你该知道 他注定
But you should know it is his destiny
要给大地带来毁灭 这是他的命运
To bring about the destruction of the earth.
不是现在 不是明天 但就在不远的将来
Not now, not tomorrow, but soon enough.
即使这样你还是要救他吗
Knowing that, you still want him to live?
孩子 做个选择吧
So, child, make the choice.
要世界 还是要他
The world or him?
要他
Him.
那时刻终会到来 而你 亲爱的
The time will come and you, my dear,
受的苦难将比任何人都多
Will suffer more than anyone.
我自己会处理
I'll deal with it.
救他好了
Now save him.
好了
It is done.
我做了我能做的
I have done what I can.
现在 只有你才能把他唤醒
Now, give him a reason to live.
嘿 朋友 别忘了那东西是我的啊
Hey, friend, what about that which is mine?
别忘了我啊 我怎么办
Don't forget about me. what about me?
朋友
Friend?
亮得刺眼啊
Shiny.
听我说 你这只大猿猴
Listen to me, you big ape.
你必须醒过来
You have to get up.
因为你要当爸爸啦
Cause you're gonna be a father.
我要当…
I become…
爸爸了
Father?
哇 好感人哦
Well, all this is very touching,
但你们要还想见努阿达 现在就得走
But if you still want to meet Nuada, we have to leave now.
准备好了
Ready.
到了
Here we are.
他们在那儿
And there they are.
70乘以70的士兵队列
Seventy times 70 soldiers.
有时我真希望自己从没把它们造出来
Sometimes I wish I'd never created them.
他们挥舞大锤
Bim-bam went the hammers!
舞过之处尽是火焰
Whoosh went the furnaces!
我的脚就是这样给烧掉的
And one of those fires took my legs off, now.
我只能走到这儿了
This is as far as I can go.
爬楼梯我可不在行
I'm not very good with steps.
要是你们是来阻止王子的 祝你们好运
But if you're here to stop him, the prince, I wish you luck then.
黄金军团绝不能苏醒
The golden army must not awaken.
弥补我们犯的过错
Undo what we did.
我们会的
We will.
你们来了
You're here.
我想你们带了剩下的碎片吧
So I assume you brought the remaining piece.
不 没带 但我们应该谈谈…
No. we didn't, but we should discuss…
别插嘴 铁罐男
I'm not addressing you, tin man.
亚伯拉罕
Abraham.
Abraham?
如我承诺的 我妹妹很好 所以…
My sister is well as I promised, so…
亚伯
Abe?
不要 亚伯拉罕
你该死的在做什么？
What the hell are you doing?
你也会为了丽兹这么做的
You would do the exact same for Liz.
不 西皮恩探员
Agent Sapien, no!
我是努阿达·西弗兰斯王子
I am prince Nuada, silverlance,
黄金军团的指挥官
Leader of the golden army.
有人想和我争权吗
Is there anyone here who would dispute my right?
杀了他们
Kill them.
但…
But…
不要啊
他骗了我们
He lied to us.
亚伯老兄 如果我们劫后余生
Abe, old buddy, if we ever get out of this,
哥俩得好好谈谈
We gotta talk.
张大嘴
Open wide!
说什么坚不可摧 放屁
Industrable, my ass.
丢过来给我
Hey! throw me a bone here!
事态不妙了
Oh, crap.
好吧 我无计可施了
Well, I'm out of ideas.
我有个主意
I got one.
我向努阿达王子挑战
I challenge prince Nuada
挑战他指挥军团的权力
For the right to command this army.
你向我挑战
You challenge me?
你算哪根葱哪根蒜
Who are you to challenge me?
无名小卒
You are nobody.
没有皇室血统
You are not royalty.
他可以 他是阿努·恩·拉玛
Yes. yes! he is Anung un Rama,
堕落者之子
Son of the fallen one.
他有权挑战
He has the right.
你必须回应
A challenge must be answered.
那好吧
Very well then.
红大个 拜托 三思啊
Red, please. Red. think about it.
他会杀了你
Guys. guys! he will kill you.
红大个 别这样做
Don't do this, red.
别担心 宝贝
Don't worry, babe.
亚伯 我不会杀了他
I'm not gonna kill him, Abe.
但我要踢烂他的屁股
But I am gonna kick his ass.
红大个
Red.
便车搭的不错吧
Nice ride, huh?
你这跳来跳去 滑头滑脑的混蛋
You jumpy, slippery bastard.
抓到你了
I got you now.
你必须杀了我 因为我不会罢手
Kill me. you must, for I will not stop.
抱歉 伙计 我不杀你
I cannot. sorry, pal.
我赢了
I win.
但你得活下去
You live.
努阿拉
Nuala.
人类
The humans,
终将抛弃你们的
They will tire of you.
他们仇视过你
They have already turned against you.
离开他们吧
Leave them.
选他们还是选我们
Is it them or us?
该选择屠杀哪一边
Which holocaust should be chosen?
我一直没有机会告诉你我的感觉
I never had a chance to tell you how I felt.
把手给我
Give me your hand.
好美
It's beautiful.
我们死了…
We die
世界会因此更加贫瘠
And the world will be poorer for it.
努阿拉 我的妹妹
Nuala, my sister.
那力量
All that power.
想都别想
Don't even think about it.
不 没什么
No. no, it's nothing.
我跟你说了这是条死胡同
I told you, it's a dead end.
做什么 走开
What are you doing? go away.
查看腰带上的定位器
Check the belt locator.
查看腰带上的定位器 那里
Check the belt locators, over there.
那里
Over there.
小子 你们并未获准开走飞机
You, you took that plane without an authorization, young man.
曼宁
Hey. Manning.
我如往常一样来帮你了
Here to help as always.
怎么了 怎么了
What's going on? what's going on?
我不干了
I quit.
什么 你说真的
What? are you serious?
看看我的样子 还不够认真吗
Looks that way, doesn't it?
你们怎么回事 不能都不干啊
What's wrong with you? you can't all just quit.
看看我们
Watch us.
回头一想
On second thought,
我应该留着这个
I think I'll keep this.
等等 等等
Come on. come on!
乔汉 不能这样的 你得阻止他们
Johann, they can't do this. stop them.
曼宁博士 回家吃屎去吧
Dr. Manning, suck my ectoplasmic schwanzstucker.
你之前怎么说的
So what you said before,
我们去哪儿定居好
About us living anywhere.
喂 你们
Guys. guys!
- 哪里都好 你和我 - 回来
- Anywhere. you and me. - Come on back.
一起在乡下找个地方
Let's find a place in the country.
叫你们回来
I said come on back.
空气清新 绿草如茵
Clean air. green hills.
一个有很多房间的大院子
A yard with lots of room to grow in.
这对宝宝会很好
It'll be great for the baby.
是宝宝们
Babies.